I'm not here to tell you a
success story. I'm not here to inspire
you, but I'm here because I'm still
in it and I think some of
you are too. My name is Roz
and I'm AuDHD, autistic and ADHD in
the same body every single day. I
was diagnosed at 46. I've been
a SEND teacher for over 20 years
and supported hundreds of neurodivergent children and
young people, but I didn't know that
I was one of them. That's what
happens to a lot of women. We
learn to mask so early, so completely.
We're told to be compliant or to
compromise or to be good. Don't argue
that even people trained to spot it
don't see it in us. And then
something strips the mask away and for
me it was perimenopause. It didn't just
kick the door in, it blew it
apart. Every coping strategy, every
compensation, every compromise, every performance of being
fine, to blend in, to fit in,
to not rock the boat, it started
to go. And what was left was
me, the raw and very unfiltered me.
And when I looked back I saw
my mum. My mum went through
something. I now have a name for
something many women have a name for
now, but many still don't. Perimenopause
as a neurodivergent woman comes with its
own complications. She didn't know that's what
it was then. She was able to
identify it later when it became more
known about, but the system didn't catch
her. My mum died in mid -March
this year and in the grief of
losing her I kept asking myself, did
anyone ever sit with her and say
what you're experiencing has a name, that
you're not broken, that you're not going
mad? She deserved that, but she never
got it. And she is not alone.
Generations of women managing and masking, getting
on with it because there was no
language for what they were carrying. I
call them the unseen generations and everything
I have built in DysPhilter, the flagship
pillar, exists because of them. Last
year I hit my own absolute limit
and I'm still coming out of it
really. A very dark place. Suicide
lideation, multiple calls to crisis and mind
in any given day. I thought I
was having a breakdown. I essentially was
having a breakdown, but what it turned
out to be was a spiritual awakening.
Things I couldn't previously see or things
I had swept under the carpet and
tried to ignore became very clear and
it was all I could see. And
then something ignited. About six to eight
weeks of the most intense hyper -focus
I have ever experienced, about six weeks
after mum died. For those of you
who don't know what audio HD hyper
-focus feels like, it doesn't care what
the clock says. It arrives at 11
o 'clock at night at one in
the morning and when it does, you're
consumed by it completely. In between
there are days I couldn't even hold
a thought in my head. Executive dysfunction
and cognitive burnout so heavy that I'd
realised I hadn't eaten or drunk anything
all day. The conditions I live with,
rejection -sensitive dysphoria, pervasive drive for autonomy,
CPTSD, PMDD, dyspraxia, insomnia, they
don't sit separately, they amplify one another.
And all of this, the lived experience,
the 20 years as a SEND teacher
and inclusion lead, watching young people fall
through every gap the system has and
losing my mum, navigating the bereavement while
building this platform. Every bit of it,
every ounce of it is in DysPhilter.
For the last six months I've been
living inside the very systems DysPhilter is
designed to fix, not theoretically, but as
a service user right now. My health
assessment has been cancelled for the third
time in a row. The first time
they left a voicemail, I rang them
back and I said, just so you
know I've got ADHD and I'm autistic,
for your reference. The response from the
lady on the end of the phone
was, I'm not trained for that, in
that tone. I hadn't asked her to
be trained for anything. I told her
who I am and that's what she
said she wasn't trained for. Two days
ago, another voicemail, another cancellation, the
same thing, and then she said I'm
just the receptionist. Then she told me
I was the last case of the
day for the appointment that was booked
in. The appointment was for 3 .30pm.
She said it was unlikely to go
ahead if the nurse over ran. So
I said I really struggle with transitions,
so is it possible we can just
reschedule now and get ahead of the
game? She said no I can't reschedule,
I can't do that. So we waited
for the day and the nurse over
ran. My appointment was not going to
go ahead. So
I think I will now be removing
myself from that circus because it's
just, I can't keep, it's
okay for them to cancel on me
three times, but if I had the
audacity or any adverse life experiences
going on of which there are plenty,
if I was to turn around to
them and say I couldn't make my
health assessment for the third time, they'd
drop me. I'm cognitively spent from
all of this, from everything. My nervous
system is maxed out and the services
that are supposed to be helping me
are not trained to talk to the
people they serve. What would the right
-of -response have been to have helped
me with that phone call? Maybe something
like, thank you for telling me, is
there anything you need for this call?
That's it. That response, the one that
never came, is in the platform. And
then there's the DWP checking on me.
Am I looking for work? Not how
are you? Not how are things going
for you, but am I looking for
work? Then sending me for a health
assessment that got cancelled for the third
time to see if I can raise
my arms above my head or walk
20 metres. I can raise my arms
above my head and walk 20 metres,
but putting me in a working
space that has overhead glaring lighting, acoustics
that will make me feel like I'm
living hell, in a living hell, dealing
with conflicting traits and needs of autism
and ADHD, having executive dysfunction, pervasive
drive for autonomy, so I struggle with
people demanding things of me because I
just see it as an absolute threat.
Rejection -sensitive dysphoria, CPTSD and trauma, they
want to know. They want to put
me in a little box in a
little job if I can raise my
arms above my head and walk 20
metres. It doesn't work like that for
neurodivergent individuals. I'm not shying away from
work. In fact, I've been working the
hardest I've ever worked in my life.
I tell them I'm building a platform
that will be helping a lot of
people like me and they hear she's
not in work. In their system, I'm
unemployed, not founder in inverted commas or
not builder of inverted commas, but
the word that goes in their boxes
is unemployed. I should be resting. I
keep being told this by my GP
and my therapist. You need to give
your brain a break. You need to
heal. You need to grieve. You need
to let yourself work through all the
things you're working through. The chance would
be a fine thing. My mum died
in March and instead of support, the
DWP are causing me more stress than
my nervous system can handle. That is
the system and that is why DysPhilter
exists. While I'm navigating all of that,
I am also still grieving. My mum
died in March and what I learned
very quickly is that when someone dies,
the systems do not stop. They do
not pause and they do not say
take a moment. The things I've seen
my stepfather go through, which I know
many millions of people across the world
go through. So I know this isn't
the first time this has ever been
talked about, but it's something that I've
witnessed and it's something I want to
work on and build on. The death
certificate, the probate, the frozen accounts, the
pension, the HMRC, the utility companies that
need changing, the car tax that needs
changing, everything registered to my mum, everything
my mum is involved in needs changing
and attention. It needs a phone call,
a form, a reference number, proof and
they all need it now while you
can barely get out of bed while
my stepfather is processing losing his wife
for 47 years. I built the
bereavement engine inside DysPhilter because of all
of this. One notification, the death is
registered and the certificate is referenced and
the platform begins rooting. It knows which
organisations need to be contacted, it knows
the order, it knows what each one
needs, it doesn't replace the person, it
carries them through it step by step
so that instead of facing 30 closed
doors, you face one, open one. And
then there was the time I couldn't
speak at all. The year before last
I had a suspected TIA, a mini
stroke. I was fully aware and my
mind was right there but my mouth
couldn't and wouldn't form the word. My
hand couldn't write and I could barely
text the doctor what it was that
I was going through. I was trying
to sign, I learnt Macaton and BSL1
whilst I was working in SEM provisions
and the people around me didn't know
Macaton or BSL, why would they? I
was trapped inside my own body, fully
conscious, completely unable to communicate and there
was nothing, no tool, no app, no
screen that could speak for me. There
was no button I could tap, no
way to play my own voice saying
I can hear you and I understand
everything you're saying but I can't speak
right now. That moment is in the
platform too, we're calling it the Vocal Philter.
One tap and your real voice speaks
for you, even if your hand can
barely move, even if no one in
the room, no sign language, not a
robot, not AI, your voice, the way
you actually sound because I've been that
person and I never want anyone to
be that person without a way out.
So DysPhilter has two editions, the
personal edition for you, the individual, navigating
your way through daily life in systems
that may not be built with you
in mind and the enterprise edition for
organisations and every person within them. So
for the personal edition, maybe a sensitive
topic but I want you to think
about the last time you've may have
received a message that may have made
your stomach drop or clench or do
a bit of a butterfly turnaround. It
may have come across as cruel or
manipulative, designed to unsettle you, not
an easy thing to have to rethink
about. DysPhilter has a feature called 'The
Communication Mirror.' It works on the send
side. Before a message reaches you, it
scans it. If it detects hostility, manipulation,
gaslighting or abuse in any form, in
any kind, it does not let it
through. It reflects it back to the
sender with a pro -social alternative and
if they insist on sending it anyway,
it never reaches you. It goes into
what's called the truth vault, time -stamped,
tamper -evident and court admissible. You
never have to read it and you
never have to have read it for
it to stand as evidence. But if
you do ever want to see what
was held, because some people will want
to know, DysPhilter does not just hand
it over. There are three stages. First,
Are you in a stable place right
now. Do you feel okay within yourself
to read the message? Second, do you
have someone with you? A trusted person
maybe. And third, if you are on
a healing journey, if you have actively
stepped away from the person or people
who sent you those messages, the raw
content is locked permanently. No override, no,
I changed my mind. All three, or
at least two, have to be in
place before you have access to that
content. Because people in distress reread harmful
content obsessively. For those who have sensory
processing differences, they need to read something
over and over and over again to
try and understand it. It re -traumatizes
them every single time though and this
platform creates a mandatory pause. Your
future self is protecting your present self
and that is not the system deciding
for you, that's the platform holding a
boundary you set when you are thinking
clearly. Then we have the universal passport.
How many of you have walked into
a doctor's appointment and couldn't remember what
you needed to say? You know something's
wrong. You've been living with it for
days, weeks or even months. But in
that five minute window, with the clock
ticking and them typing and not looking
at you, the words won't come. The
systems are invisible, the anxiety is invisible,
the pain is invisible and you're expected
to summon the energy to remember all
of it, explain all of it, prove
all of it from memory under pressure
in five minutes. DysPhilter changes this. The
microphone, DysPhilter's microphone, listens with your
consent, not to record you, to log.
You speak your symptoms into it when
you have the words, today, yesterday, last
Tuesday at 2 a .m. when the
pain was bad and you could actually
describe it. It captures what you say
with timestamps and builds a summary. So
when you walk into that appointment, you
don't have to remember anything. The summary
is already there. Your lived experience logged
over time ready to hand the professional,
not from memory, from evidence. And because
it logs over time, it will see
patterns and cycles when symptoms spike, when
they ease, what was happening the week
before a crash, what was different the
month the pain got worse. That is
not just evidence for one appointment, that's
evidence for a treatment plan. Your data
and your patterns and your body working
with the professional, not hoping they remember
to ask the right question in five
minutes. What I've just talked about is
the health passport. One section inside the
universal passport, which holds everything and moves
with you. Every department, every professional, every
service, all connected, diagnoses, medication,
pediatric health, women's and men's health, bereavement,
anything health related that should follow you
between professionals. Your lived experience
is evidence, not data that gets treated
as evidence. It is evidence. And
then we have the accessible conversation panel.
Before an appointment, get it all out,
however you need to. Type it, brain
dump it, speak it into DysPhilter's microphone.
DysPhilter will summarize it and share it
with the professional. It's not held privately,
just shared. So they have it, they're
accountable for it, and they cannot say
they didn't know. They have everything they
need to offer you the right services
and the best treatments that you could
possibly get and that you're entitled to.
And then there is the Vocal Philter,
your voice, kept and carried, ready when
you need it. Some of you will
know what it feels like to have
the words in your head, but no
one, no way to get them out.
Not because you can't think, because your
body or your nervous system or your
energy won't let you. So you record
when you can, at 11 at night,
when the thoughts are flowing and you
actually have the words three days before
the appointment when your brain is working,
and you can say what you needed
to say. The Vocal Philter captures your
voice, your real voice, the way you
actually sound and holds it. So when
the day comes and your energy may
have crashed, when you can't speak or
when you can barely move, one tap
in your voice is there saying what
you need to say in your voice,
not a machine reading words, you try
to get through this bit. And for
some people, it goes
further. A
degenerative condition, a stroke or something
that means their voice may not last.
They record now while they still can
and their voice stays for appointments, for
phone calls. For
the day their family needs to hear
them say, I love you, not a
clone, not generated, their actual voice
preserved, because a
voice is not just sound, it is
who you are, losing it should not
mean disappearing. The Enterprise
Edition for DysPhilter is not a diversity
and inclusion tool. It holds accountability in
three directions at once. The organization is
accountable to its clients, the organization is
accountable to its people, and the employees
accountable for their conduct toward each other,
everyone in all directions. So what
does this look like? A bank that
cannot send a hostile message to a
vulnerable customer because the communication mirror catches
it before it leaves, an employer whose
staff are accountable for how they speak
to each other, not just what they
produce, an organization that scoffs at this
today and six months later needs it
because someone on their team is going
through something they never saw coming. And
I want to say something to anyone
in a room where this platform gets
raised and someone scoffs. DysPhilter is
not only for people with a diagnosis,
it's for anyone whose life changes, an
accident, an illness, a bereavement, a
hormonal shift that strips away the coping
mechanisms you've spent decades building. The person
who scoffs today may be the person
who needs this most in six months.
So where is it all going? I
wrote to the Scotland Office of the
UK Government because Scotland has been ahead
of the rest of the UK in
how it supports neurodivergent people. Earlier this
month I received a formal letter back.
They said, it's clear that you have
put a great deal of thought and
effort into developing an innovative approach to
improving accessible communication for neurodivergent people. And
then I've shared your correspondence with HM
Treasury who are responsible for the UK
Government's financial inclusion strategy. Because
DysPhilter is not just a communication tool,
it's a financial inclusion infrastructure and if
you cannot communicate with your bank, your
benefits officer or your employer, you are
financially excluded not because you lack money
but because the systems that manage the
money were not built for the way
your brain works. And here is what
I want to tell you about that
letter. It was welcomed wholeheartedly. It
was a formal acknowledgement. It was a
step forward but it had no named
contact, no timeline, no clear next step.
And for a neurodivergent person an open
loop is genuinely destabilizing. You hold it
every day with no information about how
to move forward. And that, the very
communication style used in their reply, is
the gap DysPhilter exists to close. I've
submitted DysPhilter to the FCA, the Financial
Conduct Authority, through their Innovation Pathways Programme.
I've filed a patent covering the send
side communication intercept as well as many
other features of DysPhilter. The core technology
that stopped harmful content before it reaches
the recipient. No other platform does what
this does. And I have to be
honest, I believe that this has all
been guided. The signs and the synchronicity
the doors opening that I did not
knock on. I've been hanging on by
a thread and I was hanging on
by a thread and there are days
where I still feel that way. But
something kept showing me that this is
meant to move. So I've moved with
blind faith and trust in the process.
One thing I want to be clear
about DysPhilter does not store what it
filters. It processes communications to detect and
translate harmful content but nothing is retained.
The institutions, this platform will sit inside,
banks, NHS trusts, employers, they
need to know this. Nothing sits on
a server that's waiting to be breached
and that is the point. DysPhilter is
six to eight weeks old as a
built platform built in long linear bursts
of hyper focus between crashes and burnout
and grief and insomnia built from lived
experience, which means it was built like.
I'm not standing here with a polished
success story. I am in the middle
of this and there are some days
I'm consumed by the downloads of inspiration
in spirit fully in it. I am
building without a thought of what is
coming next. I don't even realize what
it is I'm creating. I'm just in
it, consumed. And then an hour later,
four hours later, I'm consumed by something
else, exhaustion, grief, overwhelm, the
weight of all of it landing all
at once, one minute consumed by the
divine, the next consumed by the human
and I have to let both be
what they are. I'm speaking for those
who are struggling on a daily basis,
for those who are in the depths
of despair, for those who have lost
hope and faith, or for those who
don't feel seen or heard. I've been
there, I've lived it and I'm still
working through it, but I have the
capacity to experience teach wisdom, one of
my outstanding learning mentors once told me,
and he was true and right. The
people who have been in the darkest
of places are often the ones who
can best support others through theirs, not
because they have it together, but because
they know what it is to not
have it together. And they try to
build something from that anyway to help
others. I want to end with this.
I'm not building a product. I'm building
the thing my mom needed when she
was struggling and the system didn't catch
her. I'm building the thing the woman
before her needed and never had. I'm
building the thing I needed at my
darkest point when there was nothing there
to catch me. And I'm building the
thing I desperately need right now to
help me function on a day to
day basis. And I'm building it so
the next generation, the young women who
don't yet know they're neurodivergent, who are
masking their way through systems that were
never built for them, do not have
to go through what any of us
went through without something there to catch
them. The system failed us, so we
built the shield. And before I close,
there's something practical I want to leave
with you. DysPhilter can be funded through
access to work, a UK government grant.
You do not have to pay it
back and it doesn't affect your other
benefits. If you are employed and you
have any condition that affects how you
work, you can apply. If you are
self employed, 100 % funding is there.
You can apply at gov .uk forward
slash access to work or call 0800
121 7479. The
QR code should be on the screen
now. So scan it and save it
and send it to someone who needs
it. And while you're here, protect your
peace and protect your energy. Whatever you
carry into tomorrow, hold on to those
two things. They are yours, not for
systems to drain or for institutions that
ask you to perform your way through
your own pain. Protect them and remember,
experience, teach wisdom.