I'm not here to tell you a
success story. I'm not here to inspire
you, but I'm here because I'm still
in it and I think some of
you are too. My name is Roz
and I'm AuDHD, autistic and ADHD in
the same body every single day. I
was diagnosed at 46. I've
been a SEND teacher for over 20
years and supported hundreds of neurodivergent children
and young people, but I didn't know
that I was one of them. That's
what happens to a lot of women.
We learn to mask so early, so
completely. We're told to be compliant or
to compromise or to be good. Don't
argue that even people trained
to spot it don't see it in
us. And then something strips the mask
away and for me it was perimenopause.
It didn't just kick the door in,
it blew it apart. Every coping strategy,
every compensation, every compromise, every performance of
being fine, to blend in, to fit
in, to not rock the
boat, it started to go. And what
was left was me, the raw and
very unfiltered me. And
when I looked back I saw my
mum. My mum went
through something. I now have a name
for something many women have a name
for now, but many still don't. Perimenopause
as a neurodivergent woman comes with its
own complications. She didn't know that's
what it was then. She was able
to identify it later when it became
more known about, but the system didn't
catch her. My mum died
in mid March this year and in
the grief of losing her I kept
asking myself, did anyone ever sit
with her and say what you're experiencing
has a name, that you're not broken,
that you're not going mad? She deserved
that, but she never got it. And
she is not alone. Generations of women
managing and masking, getting on with
it because there was no language for
what they were carrying. I call them
the unseen generations and everything I have
built in DysPhilter, the flagship pillar, exists
because of them. Last year
I hit my own absolute limit and
I'm still coming out of it really.
A very dark place. Suicide lideation, multiple
calls to crisis and mind in any
given day. I thought I was having
a breakdown. I essentially was having a
breakdown, but what it turned out to
be was a spiritual awakening. Things I
couldn't previously see or things I had
swept under the carpet and tried to
ignore became very clear and it was
all I could see. And then
something ignited. About six to
eight weeks of the most intense hyper
focus I have ever experienced, about six
weeks after mum died. For those
of you who don't know what AuDHD
hyper focus feels like, it doesn't care
what the clock says. It arrives at
11 o o'clock at night at one
in the morning and when it does,
you're consumed by it completely. In
between there are days I couldn't even
hold a thought in my head. Executive
dysfunction and cognitive burnout so heavy
that I'd realised I hadn't eaten or
drunk anything all day. The conditions
I live with, rejection -sensitive dysphoria, pervasive
drive for autonomy, CPTSD, PMDD,
dyspraxia, insomnia, they don't sit separately,
they amplify one another. And all
of this, the lived experience, the 20
years as a SEND teacher and inclusion
lead, watching young people fall through every
gap the system has and losing my
mum, navigating the bereavement while building this
platform. Every bit of it, every ounce
of it is in DysPhilter. For the
last six months I've been living inside
the very systems DysPhilter is designed to
fix, not theoretically, but as a
service user right now. My health
assessment has been cancelled for the third
time in a row. The first time
they left a voicemail, I rang them
back and I said, just so you
know I've got ADHD and I'm autistic,
for your reference. The response from the
lady on the end of the phone
was, I'm not trained for that, in
that tone. I hadn't asked
her to be trained for anything. I
told her who I am and that's
what she said she wasn't trained for.
Two days ago, another voicemail, another cancellation,
the same thing, and then she said
I'm just the receptionist. Then she told
me I was the last case of
the day for the appointment that was
booked in. The appointment was for 3
.30pm. She said it was unlikely to
go ahead if the nurse over ran.
So I said I really struggle with
transitions, so is it possible we can
just reschedule now and get ahead of
the game? She said no I can't
reschedule, I can't do that. So we
waited for the day and the nurse
over ran. My appointment was not going
to go ahead. So
I think I will now be removing
myself from that circus because it's
just, I can't keep, it's
okay for them to cancel on me
three times, but if I had the
audacity or any adverse life
experiences going on of which there are
plenty, if I was to turn around
to them and say I couldn't make
my health assessment for the third time,
they'd drop me. I'm cognitively
spent from all of this, from everything.
My nervous system is maxed out and
the services that are supposed to be
helping me are not trained to talk
to the people they serve. What would
the right -of -response have been to
have helped me with that phone call?
Maybe something like, thank you for telling
me, is there anything you need for
this call? That's it. That response, the
one that never came, is in the
platform. And then there's the DWP checking
on me. Am I looking for work?
Not how are you? Not how are
things going for you, but am I
looking for work? Then sending me for
a health assessment that got cancelled for
the third time to see if I
can raise my arms above my head
or walk 20 metres. I can raise
my arms above my head and walk
20 metres, but putting me
in a working space that has overhead
glaring lighting, acoustics that will
make me feel like I'm living hell,
in a living hell, dealing
with conflicting traits and needs of
autism and ADHD, having executive dysfunction,
pervasive drive for autonomy, so I struggle
with people demanding things of me because
I just see it as an absolute
threat. Rejection -sensitive dysphoria, CPTSD
and trauma, they want to know. They
want to put me in a little
box in a little job if I
can raise my arms above my head
and walk 20 metres. It doesn't work
like that for neurodivergent individuals. I'm not
shying away from work. In fact, I've
been working the hardest I've ever worked
in my life. I tell them I'm
building a platform that will be helping
a lot of people like me and
they hear she's not in work. In
their system, I'm unemployed, not founder in
inverted commas or not builder of inverted
commas, but the word that goes in
their boxes is unemployed. I
should be resting. I keep being told
this by my GP and my therapist.
You need to give your brain a
break. You need to heal. You need
to grieve. You need to let yourself
work through all the things you're working
through. The chance would be a fine
thing. My mum died in March and
instead of support, the DWP are causing
me more stress than my nervous system
can handle. That is the system and
that is why DysPhilter exists. While I'm
navigating all of that, I am also
still grieving. My mum died in March
and what I learned very quickly is
that when someone dies, the systems do
not stop. They do not pause and
they do not say take a moment.
The things I've seen my stepfather go
through, which I know many millions of
people across the world go through. So
I know this isn't the first time
this has ever been talked about, but
it's something that I've witnessed and it's
something I want to work on and
build on. The death certificate, the
probate, the frozen accounts, the pension, the
HMRC, the utility companies that need
changing, the car tax that needs changing,
everything registered to my mum, everything my
mum is involved in needs changing and
attention. It needs a phone call, a
form, a reference number, proof and they
all need it now while you can
barely get out of bed while my
stepfather is processing losing his wife for
47 years. I built
the bereavement engine inside DysPhilter because of
all of this. One notification, the
death is registered and the certificate is
referenced and the platform begins rooting. It
knows which organisations need to be contacted,
it knows the order, it knows what
each one needs, it doesn't replace the
person, it carries them through it step
by step so that instead of facing
30 closed doors, you face one, open
one. And then there was the time
I couldn't speak at all. The year
before last I had a suspected TIA,
a mini stroke. I was fully aware
and my mind was right there but
my mouth couldn't and wouldn't form the
word. My hand couldn't write and I
could barely text the doctor what it
was that I was going through. I
was trying to sign, I learnt Macaton
and BSL1 whilst I was working in
SEM provisions and the
people around me didn't know Macaton or
BSL, why would they? I was
trapped inside my own body, fully conscious,
completely unable to communicate and there was
nothing, no tool, no app, no
screen that could speak for me. There
was no button I could tap, no
way to play my own voice saying
I can hear you and I understand
everything you're saying but I can't speak
right now. That moment is in the
platform too, we're calling it the Vocal Philter.
One tap and your real voice speaks
for you, even if your hand can
barely move, even if no one in
the room, no sign language, not a
robot, not AI, your voice, the
way you actually sound because I've been
that person and I never want anyone
to be that person without a way
out. So DysPhilter has
two editions, the personal edition for
you, the individual, navigating your way
through daily life in systems that may
not be built with you in mind
and the enterprise edition for organisations and
every person within them. So for
the personal edition, maybe a sensitive topic
but I want you to think about
the last time you've may have received
a message that may have made your
stomach drop or clench or do
a bit of a butterfly turnaround. It
may have come across as cruel or
manipulative, designed to unsettle you, not
an easy thing to have to rethink
about. DysPhilter has a feature called
'The Communication Mirror.' It works on the
send side. Before a message reaches you,
it scans it. If it detects hostility,
manipulation, gaslighting or abuse in any
form, in any kind, it does not
let it through. It reflects it back
to the sender with a pro -social
alternative and if they insist on sending
it anyway, it never reaches you. It
goes into what's called the truth vault,
time -stamped, tamper -evident and court admissible.
You never have to read it and
you never have to have read it
for it to stand as evidence. But
if you do ever want to see
what was held, because some people will
want to know, DysPhilter does not just
hand it over. There are three stages.
First, Are you in a stable place
right now. Do you feel okay within
yourself to read the message? Second, do
you have someone with you? A trusted
person maybe. And third, if
you are on a healing journey, if
you have actively stepped away from the
person or people who sent you those
messages, the raw content is locked permanently.
No override, no, I changed my mind.
All three, or at least two, have
to be in place before you have
access to that content. Because people
in distress reread harmful content obsessively.
For those who have sensory processing differences,
they need to read something over and
over and over again to try and
understand it. It re -traumatizes them
every single time though and this platform
creates a mandatory pause. Your
future self is protecting your present self
and that is not the system deciding
for you, that's the platform holding a
boundary you set when you are thinking
clearly. Then we have the universal passport.
How many of you have walked into
a doctor's appointment and couldn't remember what
you needed to say? You know something's
wrong. You've been living with it for
days, weeks or even months. But in
that five minute window, with the clock
ticking and them typing and not looking
at you, the words won't come. The
systems are invisible, the anxiety is invisible,
the pain is invisible and you're expected
to summon the energy to remember all
of it, explain all of it, prove
all of it from memory under pressure
in five minutes. DysPhilter changes this.
The microphone, DysPhilter's microphone, listens
with your consent, not to record you,
to log. You speak your symptoms into
it when you have the words, today,
yesterday, last Tuesday at 2 a .m.
when the pain was bad and you
could actually describe it. It captures what
you say with timestamps and builds a
summary. So when you walk into that
appointment, you don't have to remember anything.
The summary is already there. Your lived
experience logged over time ready to hand
the professional, not from memory, from
evidence. And because it logs over time,
it will see patterns and cycles when
symptoms spike, when they ease, what
was happening the week before a crash,
what was different the month the pain
got worse. That is not just evidence
for one appointment, that's evidence for a
treatment plan. Your data and your patterns
and your body working with the professional,
not hoping they remember to ask the
right question in five minutes. What
I've just talked about is the health
passport. One section inside the
universal passport, which holds everything and
moves with you. Every department, every
professional, every service, all connected,
diagnoses, medication, pediatric health,
women's and men's health, bereavement, anything
health related that should follow you between
professionals. Your lived experience
is evidence, not data that gets
treated as evidence. It is evidence. And
then we have the accessible conversation panel.
Before an appointment, get it all out,
however you need to. Type it, brain
dump it, speak it into DysPhilter's microphone.
DysPhilter will summarize it and share it
with the professional. It's not held privately,
just shared. So they have it, they're
accountable for it, and they cannot say
they didn't know. They have everything they
need to offer you the right services
and the best treatments that you could
possibly get and that you're entitled to.
And then there is the Vocal Philter,
your voice, kept and carried, ready
when you need it. Some of
you will know what it feels like
to have the words in your head,
but no one, no way to get
them out. Not because you can't think,
because your body or your nervous system
or your energy won't let you. So
you record when you can, at 11
at night, when the thoughts are flowing
and you actually have the words three
days before the appointment when your brain
is working, and you can say what
you needed to say. The Vocal Philter
captures your voice, your real voice, the
way you actually sound and holds it.
So when the day comes and your
energy may have crashed, when you can't
speak or when you can barely move,
one tap in your voice is there
saying what you need to say in
your voice, not a machine reading words,
you try to get through this
bit. And for some people, it
goes further. A
degenerative condition, a stroke or
something that means their voice may not
last. They record now while
they still can and their voice stays
for appointments, for phone calls.
For the day their family needs to
hear them say, I love you, not
a clone, not generated, their
actual voice preserved, because
a voice is not just sound, it
is who you are, losing it should
not mean disappearing. The
Enterprise Edition for DysPhilter is not
a diversity and inclusion tool. It
holds accountability in three directions at once.
The organization is accountable to its clients,
the organization is accountable to its people,
and the employees accountable for their conduct
toward each other, everyone in all directions.
So what does this look like? A
bank that cannot send a hostile message
to a vulnerable customer because the communication
mirror catches it before it leaves, an
employer whose staff are accountable for how
they speak to each other, not just
what they produce, an organization that scoffs
at this today and six months later
needs it because someone on their team
is going through something they never saw
coming. And I want to say something
to anyone in a room where this
platform gets raised and someone scoffs. DysPhilter
is not only for people with a
diagnosis, it's for anyone whose life
changes, an accident, an illness, a
bereavement, a hormonal shift that strips away
the coping mechanisms you've spent decades building.
The person who scoffs today may be
the person who needs this most in
six months. So
where is it all going? I wrote
to the Scotland Office of the UK
Government because Scotland has been ahead of
the rest of the UK in how
it supports neurodivergent people. Earlier this
month I received a formal letter back.
They said, it's clear that you have
put a great deal of thought and
effort into developing an innovative approach
to improving accessible communication for neurodivergent
people. And then I've shared
your correspondence with HM Treasury who are
responsible for the UK Government's financial inclusion
strategy. Because DysPhilter is
not just a communication tool, it's a
financial inclusion infrastructure and if
you cannot communicate with your bank, your
benefits officer or your employer, you are
financially excluded not because you lack money
but because the systems that manage the
money were not built for the way
your brain works. And here is what
I want to tell you about that
letter. It was welcomed wholeheartedly. It
was a formal acknowledgement. It was a
step forward but it had no named
contact, no timeline, no clear next step.
And for a neurodivergent person an open
loop is genuinely destabilizing. You
hold it every day with no information
about how to move forward. And that,
the very communication style used in their
reply, is the gap DysPhilter exists to
close. I've submitted DysPhilter to
the FCA, the Financial Conduct Authority, through
their Innovation Pathways Programme. I've
filed a patent covering the send side
communication intercept as well as many other
features of DysPhilter. The core technology that
stopped harmful content before it reaches the
recipient. No other platform does what this
does. And I have to be honest,
I believe that this has all been
guided. The signs and the synchronicity the
doors opening that I did not knock
on. I've been hanging on by a
thread and I was hanging on by
a thread and there are days where
I still feel that way. But something
kept showing me that this is meant
to move. So I've moved with blind
faith and trust in the process. One
thing I want to be clear about
DysPhilter does not store what it filters.
It processes communications to detect and translate
harmful content but nothing is retained. The
institutions, this platform will sit inside, banks,
NHS trusts, employers, they need
to know this. Nothing sits on a
server that's waiting to be breached and
that is the point. DysPhilter is
six to eight weeks old as a
built platform built in long linear bursts
of hyper focus between crashes and burnout
and grief and insomnia built from lived
experience, which means it was built like.
I'm not standing here with a polished
success story. I am in the middle
of this and there are some days
I'm consumed by the downloads of inspiration
in spirit fully in it. I am
building without a thought of what is
coming next. I don't even realize what
it is I'm creating. I'm just in
it, consumed. And then an hour
later, four hours later, I'm consumed by
something else, exhaustion, grief, overwhelm,
the weight of all of it landing
all at once, one minute consumed by
the divine, the next consumed by the
human and I have to let both
be what they are. I'm speaking for
those who are struggling on a daily
basis, for those who are in the
depths of despair, for those who have
lost hope and faith, or for those
who don't feel seen or heard. I've
been there, I've lived it and I'm
still working through it, but I have
the capacity to experience teach wisdom,
one of my outstanding learning mentors once
told me, and he was true and
right. The people who have been in
the darkest of places are often the
ones who can best support others through
theirs, not because they have it together,
but because they know what it is
to not have it together. And they
try to build something from that anyway
to help others. I want
to end with this. I'm not building
a product. I'm building the thing my
mom needed when she was struggling and
the system didn't catch her. I'm building
the thing the woman before her needed
and never had. I'm building the thing
I needed at my darkest point when
there was nothing there to catch me.
And I'm building the thing I desperately
need right now to help me function
on a day to day basis. And
I'm building it so the next generation,
the young women who don't yet know
they're neurodivergent, who are masking their way
through systems that were never built for
them, do not have to go through
what any of us went through without
something there to catch them. The system
failed us, so we built the shield.
And before I close, there's something practical
I want to leave with you. DysPhilter
can be funded through access to work,
a UK government grant. You do not
have to pay it back and it
doesn't affect your other benefits. If you
are employed and you have any condition
that affects how you work, you can
apply. If you are self employed, 100
% funding is there. You can
apply at gov .uk forward slash access
to work or call 0800 121 7479.
The QR code should be on the
screen now. So scan it and save
it and send it to someone who
needs it. And while you're here, protect
your peace and protect your energy. Whatever
you carry into tomorrow, hold on to
those two things. They are yours, not
for systems to drain or for institutions
that ask you to perform your way
through your own pain. Protect them and
remember, experience, teach wisdom.